<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Bear with Claws</title>
 <link href="http://bearwithclaws.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://bearwithclaws.com/"/>
 <updated>2011-08-25T00:42:42+08:00</updated>
 <id>http://bearwithclaws.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Lim Cheng Soon</name>
   <email>me@bearwithclaws.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Workplaces</title>
   <link href="http://bearwithclaws.com/2011/08/24/workplaces.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-24T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://bearwithclaws.com/2011/08/24/workplaces</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;24 August 2011 - Georgetown, Penang&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/home.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My home office&quot; /&gt;
I've been working from home for the past couple of years. Home office mixes up my life with my work. I wake up. I work. I go back to sleep. There is also no sense of urgency. I feel like I have all the time in the world. It's a great place to learn and obtain new skills -- as learning takes time and patience, which the comfort of home provides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/starbucks.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Working with my friend Philip at Starbucks&quot; /&gt;
When I got bored at home, I work at Starbucks. Starbucks is lively, noisy and full of people. It's rejuvenating. It makes me feel connected to the rest of the world. And because of that, I often think of new ideas while working at Starbucks. &lt;a href=&quot;http://hackermonthly.com&quot;&gt;Hacker Monthly&lt;/a&gt; is one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/fluentspace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fluent Space&quot; /&gt;
More than a month ago, I moved out from my home in Penang to join a co-working space -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://fluentspace.my&quot;&gt;Fluent Space&lt;/a&gt; in the Klang valley. Fluent Space is spacious, well-designed and quiet. And I'm surrounded by all these awesome, like-minded people. I feel like I could take on any anything. At Fluent Space, I've been able to work on hard problems which I've been avoiding. Well, the unlimited supply of coffee certainly helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/boothk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BootHK&quot; /&gt;
I've also visited &lt;a href=&quot;http://boot.hk&quot;&gt;BootHK&lt;/a&gt;, a co-working space in Hong Kong few months ago. It certainly had a different atmosphere compare to Fluent Space. Everybody just sat around this big table, in a not-so-big room, with an intense look on their face, hustling. It felt like startups. I'd love to work there for a couple of month and see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;remarks&quot;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Photo credit:&lt;/strong&gt; Dennie Yeap a.k.a my wife ;)
&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>